What is 2 plus 2?
二加二等于几？
Incorrect.
错误。
You have been in an induced coma.
你一直处于人工昏迷状态。
You may experience some memory loss.
你可能会有些记忆丧失。
Difficulty speaking.
说话困难。
Your body movement detected.
检测到你的身体在动。
For your own safety, please return to the medical platform.
为了你的安全， 请返回医疗平台。
Please remember muscle function.
请尝试恢复肌肉功能。
has not yet opened the door.
门还没有打开。
Why is there an atomic resolution scanning electron microscope?
为什么这里有原子分辨率 扫描电子显微镜？
Why do I know that?
我怎么知道这个？
Am I fu -
我他妈的——
I can't be the only person here, right?
这里不可能只有我一个人，对吧？
No, no, no, no. That's a pilot.
不不不不，那是飞行员。
Called Houston.
叫休斯顿。
Operation Go Home, in effect.
「回家行动」，正式启动。
That's the sign.
就是那个信号。
There it is. So, what are we, like, Neptune -ish?
就是它。那么我们现在大概在， 海王星附近？
Let's crank up the radio and call Earth.
打开无线电联系地球吧。
Oh.
哦。
No. Nope.
不对。不行。
You're wrong. I need a bathroom.
你说错了。我需要去洗手间。
Ha,
哈，
ha, ha, ha.
哈哈哈。
Jonathan.
乔纳森。
So what can you tell us about the ArcLight probe?
那么关于「弧光」探测器， 你能告诉我们什么？
What do we expect to find?
我们预期会发现什么？
The image we see will be coming from the onboard microphone.
我们看到的画面来自 飞船上的麦克风。
Sound waves are physical, and at different
声波是物理现象，在不同的
frequencies, they make difference.
频率下，它们会产生差异。
Tatter, no patter, they make difference.
不同的节奏，它们会产生差异。
Olivia, can you help me out? Try going. There we go.
奥利维亚，能帮我试试吗？好的，来了。
Whoa.
哇。
Yeah. Are they really eating the sun, the space dogs?
对，它们真的在吃太阳吗？ 那些太空狗？
That is a great question.
这是个很好的问题。
right? Can I be curious what your parents think about that? I'm not sure
你父母对此怎么看？我不确定
should come from me. Hey, who wants to play a game of The Beanbag is Lava?
这应该由我来说。嘿，谁想 玩「豆袋就是熔岩」的游戏？
Lava! Lava!
熔岩！熔岩！
Lava! Lava! Lava! Lava! Lava! Lava! Lava!
熔岩！熔岩！熔岩！熔岩！熔岩！熔岩！ 熔岩！
Lava! Lava!
熔岩！熔岩！
You can't pass.
你不能通过。
Two years ago, a radio telescope enthusiast
两年前，一位业余射电望远镜爱好者
named Marina Petrova, she noticed that there was a streak of infrared light
叫玛丽娜·彼得罗娃，她注意到 有一道红外光
the sun to Venus.
从太阳延伸到金星。
And that is now known as the Pittsburgh Line. That's it.
现在这道光被称为「匹兹堡线」。就是这个。
That's the dot?
就是那个光点？
They think so.
他们是这么认为的。
What dot?
什么光点？
They sent a probe up to the Petrova line, and this is what they found.
他们向彼得罗娃线发射了一个探测器， 这就是他们发现的东西。
Are they eating the sun?
它们在吃太阳吗？
They seem to be dimming the sun a tiny, teeny, weeny little bit.
它们似乎让太阳稍微变暗了一点点， 非常非常微小。
So no big one?
所以不是大问题？
It's a small one.
是小问题。
It's a small to medium one.
是中小问题。
Over the next 30 years, the Earth could cool maybe 10 to...
在接下来的30年里，地球可能会冷却大约10到……
This is 15 degrees.
这是15度。
So it is a big world. I heard that all the crops will die, the economy will
所以这是大问题。我听说所有庄稼都会死， 经济会崩溃，
fall, and half the earth will die of starvation.
地球一半的人口会饿死。
We're all going to die.
我们都会死。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，那是真的。
You're forgetting something. Guys, guys, that's if that were to happen, right?
你们忘了一件事。大家大家， 那是如果真的发生的话，对吧？
They're going to figure this out.
他们会解决这个问题的。
Right now, the best mind in the entire world.
现在，全世界最聪明的人。
Monday morning, with no way to hold my head, it didn't hurt.
周一早上，虽然头很重， 但并不痛苦。
And the fear I had for breakfast wasn't bad, so I
早饭时的恐惧也不算太坏，所以
had one more for dessert.
我又多吃了一份甜点。
Then I headed back for home and somewhere far away...
然后我踏上回家的路， 在某个遥远的地方……
On the Sunday morning sidewalk,
在周日早晨的人行道上，
wishing love I was gone.
希望我所爱的人能离开。
Don't say something you said to me.
别再说那些话了。
Goodbye and be alone.
再见，独处吧。
We'll be right back.
我们马上回来。
Knock, knock.
叩叩。
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
Not good at jokes.
我不擅长讲笑话。
Not good at jokes, who?
「不擅长讲笑话」是谁？
Maybe.
也许。
Me.
是我。
Did you write this?
这是你写的吗？
Oh. I'm interested in this section here, page 31.
哦。我对这一部分很感兴趣， 第31页。
The Goldilocks Zone is for idiots why everyone is wrong about life.
「金发女孩区域是愚蠢的—— 为什么所有人对生命的看法都是错的」。
That was a long time ago.
那是很久以前的事了。
Did you stand by what you wrote? I was fired for standing by what I wrote.
你还坚持你写的吗？我因为坚持立场而被解雇了。
You were fired for calling the leading scholar in your field a staggering waste
你是因为在联合国教科文组织 丹麦会议上
of carbon at the UNESCO conference in Denmark.
称你领域里的顶尖学者 是「令人震惊的碳浪费」而被解雇的。
You heard about that, huh?
你也听说了，是吧？
Look, I don't know what this is, but I think that's lava.
听着，我不知道这是什么， 但我认为那是熔岩。
It's not.
不是的。
Okay.
好吧。
No one in your peers wants anything to do with you because you refuse to break
你的同行没人愿意跟你打交道， 因为你拒绝放弃
down from a very unpopular view and I can give you a chance to prove them all
一个非常不受欢迎的观点， 而我可以给你一个机会证明他们都是错的。
wrong. Uh, that's, uh, Kevin, no running. I'm not.
呃，那个，凯文，不要跑。我没有跑。
Uh, don't tell them because I don't even care.
呃，不要告诉他们，因为我根本不在乎。
Go.
去吧。
I think you do care. You're just running away because you're scared.
我觉得你确实在乎。你只是在逃跑， 因为你害怕。
Normal.
很正常。
Do you still believe water is unnecessary for life to evolve?
你还相信水对生命进化 来说是不必要的吗？
Uh...
呃……
Look, there is nothing magical about hydrogen and oxygen.
听着，氢和氧没有什么神奇的地方。
Water is required for life on Earth. Sure, but a completely different planet
水对地球上的生命来说是必需的。 当然，但一个完全不同的星球
might have completely different conditions. I don't know why that makes
可能有完全不同的条件。 我不明白为什么这让我
a nut. I need you to come with us.
成了怪人。我需要你跟我们走。
Sorry, I didn't get your name.
抱歉，我还不知道您的名字。
Carl,
卡尔，
hi. Dr. Grace, Dr. Verlaine slept us back down last night and wants you to
嗨。格雷斯博士，维尔兰博士昨晚 安排我们下来，希望你
me what they are, how they work.
告诉我们它们是什么，它们怎么工作。
I am a teacher at Grover Cleveland Middle.
我在格罗弗·克利夫兰中学教书。
Yeah, the doctorate in molecular biology.
是啊，分子生物学博士。
And I ride a bike to work.
而且我骑自行车上班。
And it's not for exercise, so I'm sure there are thousands of other people.
不是为了锻炼，所以我确信 还有数千个其他人。
It's the rays on the surface of the sun.
那是太阳表面的射线。
Does that sound like a water bridge platform to you?
这在你看来像是水桥平台吗？
I'm really dying.
我真的快死了。
Yeah.
是的。
Is all of this necessary?
这一切都有必要吗？
Yes.
有。
Am I expendable? Is that what you want me?
我是可有可无的吗？你就是这么想的？
It's almost like you don't care if I die.
感觉你根本不在乎我死活。
Hold on, you have to talk about it?
等等，你必须谈论这件事吗？
Thanks,
谢谢，
guys.
各位。
Are they alive?
它们是活的吗？
They're moving.
它们在动。
So they're alive.
所以它们是活的。
Yes, they're moving, but that could be for many reasons.
是的，它们在动，但原因可能很多。
What have they made of?
它们是由什么构成的？
It's going to take a long time. It took like 200 years to figure out how
这需要很长时间。弄清楚细菌如何工作 花了大约200年，所以……请快点。
bacteria work, so... Please do it faster.
我只是在遍历整个生命谱系。
Wow!
哇！
You're not going to believe this.
你不会相信这个的。
Nothing happened.
什么都没发生。
I can't see into these buttons.
我看不透这些按钮。
Amazing. Back sprays, microwaves, cameras, visible light.
太神奇了。反向喷射，微波， 摄像头，可见光。
Nothing.
什么都没有。
Boom, boom, boom, boom.
砰，砰，砰，砰。
I'm excited to do this all day.
我很兴奋能整天做这个。
It's a cell.
这是一个细胞。
Wake up, it's a cell!
快看，这是一个细胞！
It's a tiny alien cell.
这是一个微小的外星细胞。
Guys! Guys!
大家！大家！
This is cursed contact!
这是第一次接触！
There's a light outside of the... Uh -oh.
外面有光……哦不。
Oh, God.
哦，天哪。
What?
什么？
This is great news.
这是个好消息。
Now we can find out what they're made of.
现在我们可以弄清楚它们是由什么组成的了。
You guys fired up?
你们都准备好了吗？
Almost entirely of water.
几乎完全由水组成。
Alright.
好吧。
Sorry if I overreacted in there.
对于我刚才的过激反应，我很抱歉。
Just realizing I was wrong about the only original idea I ever had.
只是意识到我有生以来唯一 原创想法是错误的。
Yeah, what else did you learn?
是啊，你还学到了什么？
They give off infrared light when they move.
它们移动时会发出红外光。
Like so much, I don't know how they store all that energy.
多到我不知道它们怎么储存 那么多能量。
But their wavelength is exactly the petroleum frequency.
但它们的波长恰好是石油频率。
Their light is how they move. Yeah, they consume the sun's energy and then they
它们的光就是它们移动的方式。是的， 它们消耗太阳能量，然后
expel it from propulsion.
通过推进力排出。
They think it's good, basically.
他们认为基本上是好事。
Why don't we go to Venus?
我们为什么不去金星？
I have 347 other biologists from 21 countries who are organizing this week.
我已经有来自21个国家的347位 其他生物学家，这周正在组织这件事。
So, thank you for your help. I'm glad you didn't die.
所以，谢谢你的帮助。 很高兴你没有死。
Let's pack this up.
把这些打包吧。
That's it.
就这样。
That's it, Colonel.
就这样，长官。
You're taking all this stuff?
你要把这些东西都带走？
At the school you said there were thousands of people more qualified than
在学校时你说有数千人 比你更有资格，
so... I'm being modest.
所以……我只是谦虚。
I don't need modest. I need people who think they're right when everyone else
我不需要谦虚。我需要那种 在所有人都认为他们错了时
thinks they're wrong. I need people who piss other people off. That's me.
还坚持认为自己是对的人。 我需要那种惹人烦的人。那就是我。
Do you want to be on a project?
你愿意加入一个项目吗？
If you... If you think I can help, then just answer the question.
如果你……如果你认为我能帮上忙， 那就直接回答问题。
I want to help the world. I left you three dogs.
我想帮助这个世界。我给你留了三只狗。
Just three?
才三只？
That's one you killed.
那是你杀死的那一只。
I would take the three.
那我要那三只。
Yes? I'll take the dog.
是吗？那我要那只狗。
Good to work, Dr. Grace.
很高兴与你共事，格雷斯博士。
The world is counting on you.
世界在依靠你。
that you're an interstellar microorganism.
说你是一种星际微生物。
I'm not doing that.
我不打算这样做。
Why would you leave the sun to go to Venus?
你为什么要离开太阳去金星？
Why not start with our periods closer?
为什么不从轨道更近的开始？
Maybe fresh air.
也许是为了呼吸新鲜空气。
Venus's atmosphere is mostly CO2.
金星的大气主要是二氧化碳。
Maybe that's fresh air too.
也许那对它们来说就是新鲜空气。
I don't know if there's no space dust like.
我不知道是否有太空尘埃之类的东西。
Do you have a coupon?
你有优惠券吗？
We don't need a coupon. For the government.
我们不需要优惠券。这是为了政府。
Which government?
哪个政府？
All of them.
所有政府。
So this box is Venus.
所以这个盒子代表金星。
The box is Venus.
盒子就是金星。
It's set to emit the same infrared light frequency as Venus' CO2 atmosphere.
它被设置成发出与金星 二氧化碳大气层相同的红外光频率。
So if the dots move when you turn the lights on, that means they're looking
所以如果你打开灯时光点移动， 那就意味着它们在寻找
CO2. Thus proving the Carl hypothesis.
二氧化碳。从而证明了卡尔假说。
Sick.
厉害了。
All right. All right. You ready?
好了好了，准备好了吗？
Uh -oh.
哦不。
Why you tell?
你为什么要告诉他？
The astrophages moved off the slide.
星噬体从载玻片上移走了。
Huh? We lost them.
什么？我们失去它们了。
What do you mean we lost them? Go get them.
什么叫失去了？去把它们找回来。
If I open the door and the light, they're going to escape, and we'll lose
如果我打开门，灯光会让 它们逃跑，我们会永远失去它们，
forever, at least now they're in the box.
至少现在它们还在盒子里。
So we just turn the lights off?
那我们把灯关掉不就行了？
They'll still be lights. It's got to be total darkness.
还是会有光。必须完全黑暗。
Okay, so just put this box in another box.
好，那就把这个盒子 放进另一个盒子里。
and I made a baby.
然后我创造了一个小生命。
What?
什么？
We forget how the astrophage breathes.
我们忘了星噬体是怎么呼吸的。
What was that?
那是什么？
You know, Carl, when Strat said she was dead in the jet, I thought you were like
你知道，卡尔，当斯特拉特说 她在飞机上死了，我以为你是那种……
a PJ.
专业的类型。
Take this.
接住这个。
You know, a lot of times I've taken a pill from a stranger without knowing
你知道，很多次我从陌生人那里 接过一粒药，都不知道
it was.
那是什么。
In theory, just get a bunch of elbow -shaped pipes, put sunlight in one of
理论上，只需要一些肘形管道， 把阳光从一端放进去，
excuse me for a second.
打扰一下。
Write it down.
把它写下来。
And IR light and CO2 in the other.
另一端放红外光和二氧化碳。
Repeat. Anything else you need for this? Water. He gave me a pill and it's still
重复。还需要什么？水。 他给了我一粒药，它还堵在我喉咙里。
in my throat.
谢谢你。给他来点水。或者咖啡，好的。
Thank you so much. Water for him. Or coffee, yes.
非常感谢。给他点水。或者咖啡，好的。
I need those.
我需要那些。
Or not.
或者不要也行。
Okay, so this is kind of a tough rule, so don't take it personally.
好，这是个有点严格的规定， 别往心里去。
fancy. I just wanted a bed and a shower. I'm good.
fancy. 我只想要张床和淋浴。好的。
Everyone,
大家好，
this is Dr. Rylan Grace from the United States.
这位是来自美国的 瑞兰·格雷斯博士。
Please come here. Thank you. And he figured out how to breathe as a pain.
请过来。谢谢。他想出了 如何让星噬体呼吸的方法。
How did you do it?
你是怎么做到的？
Carl and I made a mini Venus out of a plywood box, and as soon as the samples
卡尔和我用胶合板箱做了个迷你金星， 一旦样本
recognized the spectral signature of CO2, they were like, whoop,
识别出二氧化碳的光谱特征， 它们就像——啊哈，
there it is.
就是这样。
While your experiment was crude and clumsy, our scientists have replicated
虽然你们的实验粗糙笨拙， 但我们的科学家已经复制了
results.
这些结果。
Sorry, how did you feel? How did you... We estimate an eight -day doubling time
抱歉，你感觉怎么样？你怎么…… 我们估计在最优条件下 倍增时间为八天。
under optimal conditions.
在最优条件下。
Dr. Grace is right.
格雷斯博士是对的。
Oh. It is the CO2.
哦。确实是二氧化碳。
That's why they're going to Venus.
这就是它们去金星的原因。
She's saying it for everyone. That's why they're going to Venus.
她在为所有人说。这就是 它们去金星的原因。
So that's why they're going to Venus, is what Dr. Grace wants to say. They're
格雷斯博士想说的就是， 这就是它们去金星的原因。它们是
going free.
自由离去的。
There it is.
就是这样。
I really like him.
我真的很喜欢他。
How long to make two million kilograms?
需要多长时间制造两百万公斤？
Two million?
两百万？
Two million is... Why on earth would you need that much
两百万是……你们到底为什么需要 那么多的
astrophage? Nobody told him. He has no clearance.
星噬体？没人告诉他。他没有许可权限。
I hereby grant you top secret clearance to all of the masons pertaining to the
我在此授予你最高机密权限， 允许你获取与
project, Hail Mary.
「万福玛利亚」计划相关的所有信息。
What's wrong, Hail Mary?
「万福玛利亚」是怎么回事？
All right.
好了。
The sun is not the only star dying.
太阳不是唯一一颗正在死亡的恒星。
There is a clear pattern of infection. Every star was infected by its neighbor
有一个明显的感染模式。 每颗恒星都被其邻居感染了，
except one.
除了一颗。
Tau Ceti? Tau Ceti, that's right. 11 .9 light years away. It is uninfected
鲸鱼座τ星？鲸鱼座τ星，没错。 距离11.9光年。它没有被感染，
despite being well within the cluster of infected stars.
尽管它就在被感染恒星群的范围之内。
Why? Why? Tell him.
为什么？为什么？告诉他。
We don't know!
我们不知道！
Which is why we decided to build a ship to go there and find out.
这就是我们决定建造一艘飞船 去那里弄清楚的原因。
It's 11 .9 miles away. We can't build an interstellar ship.
它距离11.9英里……我们造不了 星际飞船。
Oh, yeah, we can. The ship is not really the problem.
哦，当然可以。飞船本身 其实不是问题。
The energy required to power the ship is
为飞船提供动力所需的能量才是问题。
It was the problem.
曾经是问题。
Weep, weep.
哔哔哔哔。
The astrophages, the fuel.
星噬体，就是燃料。
Provided we can make it up.
前提是我们能制造出来。
And for that, we need you, my friend.
为此，我们需要你，我的朋友。
Me?
我？
Ooh, those little guys store a lot of energy.
哇，那些小家伙储存了大量能量。
One mistake in that much astrophage could vaporize California.
那么多星噬体出一点差错就能 把加利福尼亚州气化。
That's true, which is why you now live on a boat in the middle of the ocean in
没错，这就是为什么你现在住在 大洋中央的一艘船上，
here.
就在这里。
I live on a boat?
我住在船上？
You do.
是的。
So you want to build a near -light -speed spaceship, have it travel further
所以你们想建造一艘近光速飞船， 让它飞越比
any human -made object has ever traveled, and visit a star just to see
任何人造物体都更远的距离， 只是为了去看一颗恒星？
up? Yeah.
对，然后呢？
And then what?
然后呢？
There won't be enough fuel for a round trip, so they send their findings back
没有足够的燃料做往返旅行， 所以他们将把发现结果
Earth Control.
传回地球控制中心。
And the astronauts die in space.
然后宇航员死在太空里。
Any other plans you've
你还有什么其他
thought of? Anything else you're kicking around?
计划吗？还有什么其他想法？
There are infinite possibilities for this to go wrong. It almost certainly
这件事有无数种可能出错的方式。 它几乎肯定
work. It's what you Americans would call a long shot.
不会成功。用你们美国人的话说， 这是一个冒险的赌注。
Yeah, Mary.
是的，玛丽亚。
I get it.
我明白了。
The alternative is to just do nothing.
另一个选择就是什么都不做。
And to starve and to kill each other with everything on the planet going.
然后在地球上所有东西都崩溃时， 挨饿，互相残杀。
We only need three.
我们只需要三个人。
Pilot, an engineer, and a scientist.
飞行员、工程师和科学家。
Commander Yao, I must have known you, but I just don't remember.
姚指挥官，我一定认识你， 但我就是想不起来了。
You make a funny face in literally every picture.
你在每张照片里都做一个 搞笑的表情。
You must have been very smart and strong and brave.
你一定非常聪明、强壮、勇敢。
Ilyukna?
伊留克纳？
I owe you three bags of vodka.
我欠你三袋伏特加。
You seem to have had a lot of friends.
你似乎有很多朋友。
This picture of you, what looks like sneaking into the Kremlin, is
这张你似乎在偷偷溜进克里姆林宫的照片， 已经是
legendary.
传奇了。
I wish you were still here.
我希望你还在这里。
I wish I wasn't alone.
我希望我不是一个人。
I wish I was doing a better job.
我希望我做得更好。
We were both very loved.
我们两个都被深深地爱着。
You deserve much more than this.
你值得拥有比这更多的东西。
I'll do my best to make sure that you don't.
我会尽力确保你没有白白牺牲。
You know, that you didn't.
你知道，就是你没有白白牺牲。
I'll do my best.
我会尽力的。
I'm not a pilot!
我不是飞行员！
The telescope operational.
望远镜已启动。
You have a patrol line.
你有一条巡逻线。
But you're not doing it.
但你没有在执行。
Why?
为什么？
What's up with that?
怎么回事？
Nope, nope, nope. Let's go. Let's go, Mary.
不行不行不行。走了走了，玛丽。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不不不不不不不。
Pilots detected.
检测到飞行员。
Please engage restraint.
请系好安全装置。
We're getting out of here. Engage restraint.
我们要离开这里。系好安全装置。
Incorrect. Welcome to the Hill, Mary.
错误。欢迎来到万福玛利亚。
Is it this thing?
是这个东西吗？
They're sending me something.
它们在给我发送什么东西。
It could be a message.
可能是一条信息。
It could be a bomb.
也可能是一枚炸弹。
Is it a bomb?
是炸弹吗？
It killed us!
它杀了我们！
Why not?
为什么不是？
I guess there's Edgar Mozart faces, huh, Mary?
我猜这就是外星版的莫扎特， 是吧，玛丽？
What's that?
那是什么？
Why is it moving so much slower than the last one?
为什么它比上次移动得慢那么多？
If we were going
如果我们要
to catch it, what would we do?
追上它，该怎么做？
Yeah!
好！
Just crazy.
太疯狂了。
We need equipment
我们需要设备
to analyze the astrophage at our setting.
来分析我们设置中的星噬体。
Most of this equipment won't work in zero gravity.
大部分设备在零重力下无法使用。
And we haven't seen to develop and build zero gravity versions of this
我们还没来得及开发和建造 这些设备的零重力版本。
equipment. We would need years for that, and we have months.
这需要数年时间， 而我们只有几个月。
What's the alternative?
有什么替代方案？
We need zero gravity.
我们需要零重力。
Centrifuge?
离心机？
Centrifuge. They used them to make butter during the Civil War, actually.
离心机。南北战争时期他们 其实用离心机来制作黄油。
Fun. Fun fact.
有趣。有趣的小知识。
Still Xenon.
仍然是氙气。
Up is down, left is right, Xenons are solid, aliens are real. I'm wrong about
上下颠倒，左右混乱，氙气是固态的， 外星人是真实的。我对
everything and everything's wrong.
一切都是错的，一切都是错的。
The left is tidy, righty -woody.
左边整齐，右边松散。
Oh no!
哦不！
You remember this big purchase you've been dreaming of so much? It's now
你还记得你一直梦想的那笔大购买吗？现在，
possible if you win with an X -Bait.
如果你在X-Bait赢了，它成为可能。
Pariez sur n 'importe quel événement sportif. Gagnez au poker, au casino.
在任何体育赛事上下注。 在扑克和赌场赢钱。
Attaquez les paris sur les cybersports.
攻克电竞赛事的赌注。
Jouez aux machines à sous. Et vous allez pouvoir acheter ce que vous avez
玩老虎机。你将能够买到 你一直渴望的东西。
tellement voulu. Qu 'est -ce que vous attendez ? Allez maintenant sur le site
你还在等什么？ 现在就去Annexbet网站
Annexbet et obtenez un bonus de 100 % sur votre premier dépôt.
首次存款即可获得100%奖金。
want to.
想要的话。
Oh.
哦。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
You want me to
你想让我
go back in my ship?
回到我的飞船里？
But I just got here.
但我刚到这里。
Okay.
好吧。
I'll talk to you later.
我待会儿再和你说。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
I like what you've done with the gravity.
我喜欢你对重力的处理方式。
I made you a ship.
我给你做了一艘飞船。
It's ramen.
是拉面。
I only made one. I'm not sure how many of you there are.
我只做了一份。不确定你们有几个人。
Right.
对。
You can hear me when you want.
你可以在你想的时候听见我。
Wow.
哇。
I can't seem to see his face.
我好像看不清他的脸。
He's serious.
他是认真的。
His faces are overrated.
脸这东西被高估了。
You like tapping, huh?
你喜欢敲击，是吗？
You're pointing.
你在指东西。
You're not tapping. Sorry.
你不是在敲击。抱歉。
Another present.
又一份礼物。
have one of these.
有一个这样的东西。
I love it.
我喜欢。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Do I put this on my head?
我把这个戴在头上吗？
Take off my head?
把头取下来？
Take my helmet off?
把头盔摘掉？
No?
不行？
It'll... That's a big ass.
那是个……那是个很大的屁股。
this is taking a turn thank you for the what i hope is not handcuffs i'm sorry
这事情开始转变了，谢谢你给我这个 我希望不是手铐的东西，我为
about the whole helmet thing unfortunately i need oxygen to breathe
头盔的事道歉，不幸的是 我需要氧气来呼吸，
two
二
rings of eight oh two
八圈零二
This is oxygen.
这是氧气。
I still don't think I can do it, though. Sorry.
我还是觉得我做不到。抱歉。
If I'm wrong, I'm really wrong.
如果我错了，那错得离谱。
The Patrova Line.
彼得罗娃线。
We're here for the same reason.
我们在这里是出于同样的原因。
You have a Patrova Line problem, too.
你也有彼得罗娃线的问题。
You need to solve it. I need to solve it.
你需要解决它。我也需要解决它。
That's why you made me do it.
这就是你让我做这件事的原因。
I'm going to take that as a yes.
我就当这是「是」了。
We're going to save our planet, so we have to learn how to communicate.
我们要拯救各自的星球， 所以我们必须学会沟通。
You know, they say math is the universal language. I thought maybe we'd fall
你知道，他们说数学是通用语言。 我想也许我们可以
down if that's true.
验证一下这是否是真的。
See the numbers?
看到数字了吗？
Oh, you want this?
哦，你想要这个？
Whoa!
哇！
Crispus Eve, that is.
克里斯普斯·伊夫，确实是。
It's really hot in there.
里面真的很热。
Is that ammonia?
那是氨气吗？
Anyway, that's... Let's see the numbers.
不管怎样……让我们看数字。
There you go. They're on the other side.
给你。它们在另一边。
Do it again.
再做一次。
If you do it again, don't let it snap back.
如果你再做一次，别让它弹回去。
Don't do it. Don't do it. Hold it like that.
别做。别做。就这样拿着。
And you look.
然后你看。
How about something else?
换个别的怎么样？
Look at this.
看这个。
A clock.
一个时钟。
We both have time, right?
我们都有时间，对吧？
These are the hands and these are the numbers. One, two, three, they point to
这些是指针，这些是数字。一、二、三， 它们指向
the numbers.
数字。
And you'll notice there's numbers there and there's also numbers here.
你会注意到那里有数字， 这里也有数字。
Okay.
好的。
It is dark.
天黑了。
Wait. Don't... Don't go anywhere. Stay.
等等。别……别走。留下来。
Oh.
哦。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
Um... I'm Grace.
嗯……我是格雷斯。
I'm gonna call you Rocky.
我打算叫你罗基。
You know, because you look like a giant rock.
因为你看起来像一块巨大的岩石。
Oh.
哦。
Um... I'm fine.
嗯……我没事。
Echolocation, right? You need surfaces to see. Try this.
回声定位，对吧？你需要表面才能看东西。 试试这个。
You see the numbers?
你看到数字了吗？
What's that?
那是什么？
Is that good?
这样好吗？
We do this.
我们这样做。
Your version of this is our thumbs up.
你们这个动作相当于我们的大拇指朝上。
No, that's thumbs down.
不，那是大拇指朝下。
Let me do the thumbs up.
让我做大拇指朝上。
It's close enough.
差不多了。
You want me to wait?
你想让我等？
I wait?
我等？
Yeah, no.
好吧，不了。
I'm really excited to be working with you on this.
我非常兴奋能和你一起研究这个。
Fired up. Sorry I'm talking so much.
太兴奋了。对不起，我说得太多了。
It's just I haven't been around anyone in a long time.
只是我已经很久没有人陪了。
It's the clock.
是那个时钟。
I showed you a clock and... You're filling me up.
我给你看了一个时钟，然后…… 你把我装满了。
We're, uh, clock bros.
我们是「时钟兄弟」。
Right.
对。
Um, I gotta be honest, I... I'm not sure I'm getting...
嗯，说实话，我……我不确定我是否明白……
Check this out.
看这个。
I thought I might record you. Oh, no, no.
我想我可以录你。哦，不不不。
No, that's okay. Just a microphone. One second. Let's start with one.
没事，只是麦克风。 等一下。我们从一开始。
One.
一。
No, no. Wait, wait, wait. Sorry.
不不不。等等等等等。抱歉。
Okay. One.
好了。一。
to communicate your name.
来传达你的名字。
Okay, let's start with you.
好了，从你开始。
Rocky.
罗基。
You done?
你说完了吗？
My name, can't wait to hear this, is Grace.
我的名字……我很期待听到， 是格雷斯。
What's your word for my name? Go ahead.
你对我名字的称呼是什么？说吧。
You know, enough to order at restaurants. We have about 250 more.
你知道，差不多能在餐厅点菜的程度。 我们还有大约250个词。
If I had this beer, it would kill him and his beat. But I like to keep a
如果我喝了这瓶啤酒会杀死他 和他的节拍。但我喜欢在
in my relationships anyways.
我的关系里保持一定距离。
He's a mechanic, I think.
我觉得他是个机械师。
He uses a battle form of Xenon. He can make anything.
他用一种氙气的战斗形态。 他能制造任何东西。
Look at this.
看这个。
I'm calling it Xenonite.
我叫它「氙石」。
And if I can't understand what he's saying, which is most of the time, he
如果我听不懂他说的话， 大多数时候他就会
on a little puppet show for me and my tiny brain. And you know what?
给我和我的小脑袋演个小木偶戏。 你知道什么？
I don't mind that it's kind of growing on me. At least not growing in me, you
我不介意，它某种程度上吸引了我。 至少不是长在我身上，
know, which was a concern for a little while.
这让我担心了一段时间。
His son is dying too, so maybe we can help each other.
他的太阳也在消亡， 所以也许我们可以互相帮助。
Recognize this?
认识这个吗？
We call it Astrophage. It means star eater.
我们叫它「星噬体」，意思是「噬星者」。
Yeah. Same.
是啊。一样。
How did they die?
他们是怎么死的？
Oh.
哦。
Um... There were three of us and...
嗯……我们有三个人，然后……
He died on the way here.
他在来这里的途中死了。
I wish I knew why.
我真希望我知道为什么。
Ew. Oh, it's this bump, by the way.
恶心。哦，顺便说一下，就是这个鼓包。
What's that?
那是什么？
This my bump.
这是我的鼓包。
No, it's this bump.
不，是这个鼓包。
It's not the same.
不一样。
Exactly. The astrophage has to reach Talseti, otherwise we wouldn't see the
就是这样。星噬体必须到达鲸鱼座τ， 否则我们不会看到
metropolis.
那个大都市。
Do we really need this home run?
我们真的需要这个本垒打吗？
Oh boy.
哦天哪。
You know, I used to have one of these in my classroom and it was a lot simpler
你知道，我以前教室里 也有一个这样的，但设置起来
to set up.
要简单得多。
What's that? What? What?
那是什么？什么？什么？
That is a great question.
这是个很好的问题。
You know what?
你知道吗？
Why is a
为什么一个
school
学校
teacher in
老师
space?
在太空里？
Meryl Streep.
梅丽尔·斯特里普。
Why is a schoolteacher in space?
为什么一个学校老师在太空里？
She can do anything.
她什么都能做。
Why is a school in space?
为什么一所学校在太空里？
That's not bad.
这个还不错。
I like.
我喜欢。
All right. And in answer to your question, I have no idea what I'm doing
好了。而且回答你的问题， 我完全不知道我在太空
space.
做什么。
Is okay.
没关系。
Grace, find out when Grace go home.
格雷斯，查一下格雷斯什么时候回家。
How am I going to sleep?
我怎么睡觉？
No understand.
不理解。
Word.
词。
Sleep?
睡觉？
Just like this?
就这样躺着？
Dead, died, just died, died? No, not died. Just lay here for 29 ,000 seconds
死了，刚死了，死了，死了？不，没死。 只是躺在这里29000秒，
then we... Wake up. Oh, understand.
然后我们……醒来。哦，明白了。
Okay, here we go.
好，开始吧。
Good night.
晚安。
I watched Great Sleep.
我看着大睡眠。
No, that's fine. That's a little weird.
不，没关系。只是有点奇怪。
Good night.
晚安。
That's really interesting.
真的很有趣。
That sounds like something you can unpack that tomorrow.
听起来你明天可以再深入研究一下。
That's where you're going to be? No, it's usually closer.
那是你要去的地方吗？不，通常更近。
On your chest.
在你的胸口。
I wonder if it would work from a little farther back.
我想知道从稍微远一点的地方是否也有效。
But Grace won't feel comfortable and safe.
但格雷斯不会感到舒适和安全。
Well, I'm... And look, I'm seeing, um... So many sides of you, ain't we? And
嗯，我……我现在看到了，嗯…… 我们看到了你那么多面，不是吗？
it's great.
这很好。
Right now I'm seeing the underside of you.
现在我看到了你的下面。
Cut the sides before anyway. Good night.
反正先把侧面切掉。晚安。
Even though we watch each other sleep.
尽管我们互相看着对方睡觉。
Viridians don't sleep like a human does.
维里迪安人的睡眠方式不像人类。
They seem legitimately paralyzed.
他们似乎是真的在瘫痪。
If danger comes, you can't wake up.
如果危险来临，你无法醒来。
The survival norm.
这是生存规范。
Someone has to keep you safe.
必须有人保护你的安全。
It's an honor.
这是一种荣誉。
I'm excited to hear what I've learned about astrophage and spin drives.
我很期待听听我对星噬体和自旋驱动器的发现。
One thousand and nine of these little engines that could on the Hail Mary
万福玛利亚上有一千零九个这样的小发动机
Okay.
好的。
Once the mission is complete, we have the option to end our lives on our
任务完成后，我们可以选择 在我们自己的
The alternative is slow, miserable death by starvation. I want to do a lethal
另一个选择是缓慢、痛苦地 死于饥饿。我想做一个
injection of the liver with the heroin.
对肝脏注射致命剂量的海洛因。
I will have what she's having.
我想要她点的那个。
Following on from Dr. Grayson's discovery, we built an IR emitter set to
根据格雷森博士的发现，我们建造了 一个红外发射器，设置为
wavelength of CO2, which contracts the astrophage to this revolver. The drive
二氧化碳的波长，将星噬体引导到这个转盘上。 驱动器
then rotates upwards.
然后向上旋转。
We increase the IR.
我们增加红外线。
The astrophage get excited, thrust the ship forward, and so on and so on.
星噬体被激发，推动飞船向前， 如此循环。
This is...
这是……
less than a gram of astrophage, and we only need a fraction of this for the
不到一克的星噬体，而我们 只需要其中一小部分来做
fenestration in particular, to do what?
这个特定的操作，具体是做什么？
To melt a metric ton of metal.
融化一吨金属。
Powerful stuff.
威力强大。
Commander Yao, I really appreciate what you all are doing.
姚指挥官，我真的很感激 你们所做的一切。
You would do the same?
你也会这样做吗？
I would choose just not to go at all.
我宁愿选择根本不去。
I don't have the bravery gene that you all have. Trust me.
我没有你们所拥有的那种勇气基因。 相信我。
It's not a gene. You just need to find someone who will be brave for you.
这不是基因。你只需要找到 一个愿意为你勇敢的人。
You're in a ball.
你缩成一团了。
No, Rocky, no dying. Great atmosphere. I come up.
不行，罗基，不能死。大气层不错， 我可以过去。
Great and Rocky face side. Have to kill after a face together.
格雷斯和罗基要并排， 之后必须一起面对。
I keep going this way?
我一直往这边走？
This room's boring.
这个房间真无聊。
Science, favor, big air is good plan.
科学，好处，好空气是好计划。
Put this down here, Chris.
把这个放在这里，克里斯。
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿，嘿，嘿。
Rocky wanted to do human technology.
罗基想研究人类技术。
Dirty. Dirty, dirty, dirty, dirty.
脏。脏，脏，脏，脏。
Well,
嗯，
I wasn't expecting company, was I? This room for garbage?
我不是预期会有客人，不是吗？ 这个房间是用来存垃圾的？
Oh, no.
哦，不。
This is the lab. This is where the science... What's this? What's this?
这是实验室。这里是搞科学的地方…… 这是什么？这是什么？
Rocky will build work from here. We'll need much room for Rocky. And much less
罗基将在这里工作。我们需要给罗基 很多空间。给格雷斯留
space for Gray.
少一些空间。
We go for trova lines. We collect astrophage. We study it. We go home. We
我们去找彼得罗娃线。我们收集星噬体。 我们研究它。我们回家。我们
collect. We save earth. We take weeds. Uh, where?
收集。我们拯救地球。我们除去杂草。 呃，在哪里？
I see Gray.
我看到格雷斯了。
Apology. Apology. Apology. Rocky's dead. Rocky, my hand is up.
道歉。道歉。道歉。罗基死了。 罗基，我的手举起来了。
We can't just show up in a space ball and announce and move into someone
我们不能就这样突然出现在一个空间球里 然后宣布并搬进别人的
space. Right? There have to be boundaries.
空间里。对吧？必须要有边界。
Boundaries. We have one mission.
边界。我们有一个任务。
Mission. But we're two distinct individuals. Individuals. Both working
任务。但我们是两个不同的个体。 不同的个体。都在
distinct individual part of that mission. Mission.
独立地参与那个任务的不同部分。 任务。
Separately. Separately. Okay.
分开地。分开地。好的。
Where are my bedrooms?
我的卧室在哪里？
Bedrooms?
卧室？
So I have a new roommate now.
所以我现在有个新室友了。
Be careful back there, okay?
在那边小心点，好吗？
The draw wheel is pretty lopsided.
抽奖轮盘相当不均衡。
Where on earth does that go? Not on earth. More high. It goes this way? All
那东西到底去哪里？不在地球上。 更高。去这边？一直
way out to here. Yes.
延伸到这里。是的。
I was pointing.
我在指方向。
What? He tells me what to do. He tells me why to do it. He tells me how to do
什么？他告诉我做什么。他告诉我 为什么做。他告诉我怎么做。
it. He tells me when to do it.
他告诉我什么时候做。
And then when I do it, he's like, what are you doing?
然后当我做的时候，他说， 你在做什么啊？
I'm just saying you're going to get out of the ball to get into a much bigger
我只是说你要从这个球里出来， 进入一个大得多的
ball? Yes, we're sleeping.
球？是的，我们要睡觉了。
Why? You don't even use a bed.
为什么？你又不用睡床。
You don't have the, like, Hellraiser thing that you sleep on. What do you do?
你又没有那个地狱使者式的睡眠装置。 你是怎么睡的？
I'm being angry, stupid. How long since last sleep?
我很生气，愚蠢。上次睡觉是多久以前？
Don't talk to Armando. Yes.
别和阿曼多说话。是的。
Can I help you? You're doing this.
我能帮你吗？你在这样做。
It's a lot of this.
这很多。
No understand, no understand.
不理解，不理解。
And then it's like, I need a word.
然后就是，我需要一个词。
You know what the word is?
你知道那个词是什么？
Bossy. I'm like one of the villains in the Superman movie. I'm just, like,
专横。我就像超人电影里的反派一样。 我就像，
trapped in hell. Get me out of here!
困在地狱里。放我出去！
If eating happens, or...
如果进食发生，或者……
Grace looks
格雷斯看起来
disgust when he eats. How do you look when you eat? It looks beautiful.
很厌恶，当他吃东西的时候。 你吃东西时是什么样子？看起来很美。
Tell me.
告诉我。
Oh, my God.
哦，我的天啊。
He has incredible hearing.
他的听力令人难以置信。
He can see through walls.
他能看穿墙壁。
Personal space is at a premium.
个人空间非常宝贵。
Who is Grace talking to? Question.
格雷斯在和谁说话？有个问题。
There's no way you can hear me right now. Can't hear. Who are you talking to?
不可能你现在能听到我说话。 听不到。你在和谁说话？
You can hear this.
你能听到这个。
Yes, Grace, you can hear this.
是的，格雷斯，你能听到这个。
Hello, Grace. He's right here. Hello, Grace Franke.
你好，格雷斯。他就在这里。 你好，格雷斯·弗兰克。
Did Grace find sampler instruction?
格雷斯找到采样仪说明书了吗？
Yes, I found the sampler instruction.
是的，我找到了采样仪说明书。
He's really smart about something.
他在某件事上真的很聪明。
Oh, my God, he's got a gun.
哦，我的天，他有枪。
Oh, this?
哦，这个？
No, no, no.
不不不。
This to screen in front, and now this to that over here.
这连到前面的屏幕，然后这个连到那边。
Now Rocky can hear screen.
现在罗基能听到屏幕了。
Please don't play with me. Oh, point over here.
请不要拿我开玩笑。哦， 指向这边。
Yes. Oh, okay. Now over there. Your point of being, then. But this species
是的。哦，好的。现在指向那边。 你指的那个存在的目的，然后。 但这个物种
doesn't know about things like relativity and radiation.
不了解相对论和辐射之类的东西。
And the rest of the crew?
其余的船员呢？
And mid -step there. And here?
就在那一步。在这里？
And where did you keep the answer, Faith?
你把答案放在哪里了，费斯？
I think the radiation is what made the crew think, right?
我认为辐射就是让船员产生 那种想法的原因，对吧？
Yes, but they probably just protected you from it.
是的，但他们可能只是保护了你。
This isn't something that you would have fixed.
这不是你本可以修复的事情。
But I guess together we're... You know, pretty smart.
但我想我们在一起……你知道， 相当聪明。
Since we're only going to be able to intersect with the patrol line for a few
既然我们只能与巡逻线 相交几秒钟，
seconds, we're not going to have enough time to get a good sample. Too fast. Do
我们没有足够的时间 获取好的样本。太快了。来个
a puppet show. Too fast.
木偶戏。太快了。
I don't want to do the puppet show. No, do a puppet show.
我不想演木偶戏。不，演个木偶戏。
This is us.
这是我们。
Yes? Flying along. The problem is, because the solar system is constantly
是吗？在飞行中。问题是， 因为太阳系在不断移动，
moving, the patrol line is going to constantly be moving. Right? Am I still
巡逻线也会不断移动。对吧？ 我还在演吗？还在演？是，是的。 到了表演时刻了。所以我们不会
doing it? Still on it? Yes, yes. It's showtime. So we're not going to have
有足够的时间获取样本。不，不，不。
to get the sample. No, no, no.
重力随线一起移动。
gravity to move with line.
你的意思是某种程度上绕着它的轨道运行？
You mean sort of like wrapped in its orbit?
是的。
Yes.
我没想到这一点。我想到了。
I didn't think of that. I did.
我们想出了一个计划。 我们要绕着星噬体呼吸的那颗行星运行，
We figured out a plan. We're going to orbit the planet where Astrophage
收集一个样本，弄清楚 为什么它没有吃掉鲸鱼座τ。
breathes, collect a sample, figure out why it's not eating Tau Ceti.
这家伙在和谁说话？
Who is this guy talking to?
我没有在和任何人说话。
I'm not talking to anyone.
算了。这行不通。我认为我们应该
Forget it. This isn't going to work. I think we should
到达
arrive
汤森E。
at Towson E.
谢谢你，玛丽。
The beach is always changing. You can go to the same spot every day. You're
但你看到的永远是不同的海滩。
always looking at a different beach.
然后你爬上去。
And you climb.
爬到顶上。
Climb to the top.
他非常兴奋，因为我们都能回家了。
He's so excited about us both getting to go home.
假装你是专业选手。
Pretend you're pro.
触碰浪花。
Wiping it out.
哦，
Oh,
他们做到了。
they got it.
第三集，阿波罗训练他。 第七集，他训练阿波罗的孩子。
In three, Apollo trains him. And in seven, he trains Apollo's kid.
我说either，你也说either。
I say either, you say either.
不对。我说neither，你也说neither。不对。
No. I say neither, you say neither. No.
我喜欢地球。
I like earth.
岩石。
Rock.
你呢，罗克？你最想念家里的什么？
What about you, Rock? What do you make most about home?
我的伴侣。
My mate.
等等，什么？
Wait, what?
你有伴侣？
You've got a mate?
是的。我的意思是，不是你那种， 我是说，我确定，我…… 他们叫什么名字？
Yes. I mean, not that you, I mean, I'm sure, I'm... What's their name?
名字是……
Name is...
我的意思是，我有过。
I mean, I did.
但她认为我活在云端， 不太想生活在现实世界里。
But she thought I had my head in the clouds and I didn't really want to live
她是对的。
the real world.
不管怎样，现在她和马克在一起了。
She was right.
罗基恨马克。
Anyway, now she's with Mark.
但别说我了。你有伴侣。
Rocky hate Mark.
你们在一起多久了？
But enough about me. You have a mate.
186.3年。
How long you been together?
就像蜜月期一样。
186 .3 years.
现在我明白了。
Like the honeymoon phase.
那是个玩笑，罗德。那是很长时间了。 我们在一起很久了。
Now I understand.
她说她爱你，但她不能爱我。 但我爱你。
That's a joke, Rod. That's a long time. We've been together a long time.
我
She said she loves you, but she can't love me. But I love you.
不会
I
再玩窗户游戏了。
won't
怎么了？
play window anymore.
扮演你的角色。期待之一。
What's going on?
请求允许登船，船长？
Play your role. One expect.
你已经在船上了。
Permission to come aboard, Captain?
你拿到免费帽子了吗？
You're already aboard.
是的，我有点买了。哦。
Did you get your free hat?
你不唱歌，是吗？
Yeah, I kind of bought them. Oh.
是的，我唱。我其实 在一个小小的德国青年合唱团唱过歌。
You don't sing, huh?
我很好奇。
Yeah, I do. I actually sang in a little German youth choir.
来嘛。
I'm very curious.
一直都想成为那样的人。
Come on.
说太多了。
Always wanted to be.
比如现在，我不是故意来打扰你的。 你没有打扰
Talk too much.
我。这是个很奇特的派对。
Like right now, I didn't mean to bother you. You didn't bother
是吗？
me. It is such a weird party.
是啊，我在唱歌。
Is it?
大家都很开心。
Yeah, I was singing.
人们在谈恋爱，他们都知道 自己要死了。
Everyone's so happy.
同志情谊帮助我们更好地工作， 你知道吗？
People are hooking up, and they all know they're going to die.
对我来说没那么有效。
Camaraderie helps us do our job, you know?
不得不请求所有人…… 一定很难吧。
Not so much me.
是啊。
It must be hard having to ask everybody to...
那么，你觉得怎么样？
Yeah.
你觉得你会放弃吗？
So, what do you think?
什么，整件事？
Do you think you're going to blow it off?
是的。
What, the whole thing?
上帝保佑的话。
Yeah.
停止你的哭泣，这是时代的象征。
God willing.
欢迎来到最终演出。
Just stop your crying, it's a sign of the times.
希望你穿了最好的衣服。
Welcome to the final show.
你不能在飞往天空的路上搭乘门。
I hope you're wearing your best clothes.
你在这里看起来很不错， 但你其实不太好。
You can't ride the door on your way to the sky.
我猜可以再多一点……更有感染力。
You look pretty good down here, but you ain't really good.
是的。
I guess it could be a little more... evocative.
托盘已激活，两边都看。
Yep.
是时候出发了。
Trays are live, looking both ways.
你知道，在地球上， 如果你发现了什么，你可以为它命名。 你技术上是第一个来到这里的。
It's time go.
是的。名字是：中等粗糙纹理圆形星球。
You know, back on Earth, if you discover something, you get to name it. You were
好吧。
technically the first one here.
好吧，如果「中等粗糙纹理圆形星球」 已经被用了，我们就用
Yeah. The name is Medium Rough Texture Circle Planet.
也许用个人化的名字。
Okay.
人类语言里的「罗基人」这个词。
Well, if Medium Rough Texture Circle Planet was taken, we'd just have a
嗯，这很奇怪。
Maybe go with something personal.
要么
human word for Rocky Man.
不
Well, that's weird.
繁殖，要么不离开这个星球。
It's either
是什么？
not
这不只是星噬体。是细菌，
reproducing or it's not leaving the planet.
原生动物。就像地狱一样。
What is it?
和地球一样。
This is not just astrophage. It's bacteria,
这意味着什么？有个问题。
protozoa. It's like hell on earth.
如果思维控制中有一个完整活跃的生物圈， 那么似乎有理由认为
And earth.
在阿德里安上也有一个完整活跃的生物圈， 这意味着……
What does this mean? Question.
阿德里安上有生命。
If there's a whole active biosphere in the control of the mind, it seems to
不！格雷斯！格雷斯！生命！
reason there's a whole active biosphere on Adrian, which means...
生命是原因！生命是原因！
There's life on Adrian.
不不不！
No! Grace! Grace! Life!
不，不明白！
Life is reason! Life is reason!
不明白！格雷斯！格雷斯！ 生命是什么原因？生命是原因！
No, no, no!
什么？
No, no, understand!
生命是原因。生命是原因。
No, understand! Grace! Grace! Life is reason for what? Life is reason!
生命是什么原因？阿德里安上的生命 是星噬体失衡的原因。
What?
阿德里安上的生命使星噬体死亡。
Life is reason. Life is reason.
就像捕食者一样。
Life is reason what? Life on Adrian is reason astrophage imbalance.
是的。这可以保持种群稳定。
Life on Adrian makes astrophage die.
太好了。如果我们把捕食者带回家， 我们的太阳就不会死。
Like a predator.
生命是太阳不会死的原因。
Yes. That would keep the population stable.
你为什么不直接这样说？
Great. If we bring predator home, our stars not die.
在阿德里安获取某种微生物捕食者。
Life is reason star not die.
它会在星噬体呼吸的云层中。
Why didn't you just say that?
泰德。
Get some kind of microbial predator on Adrian.
哦。问题是这艘飞船 不是为进入大气层而建造的。
It'll be in the clouds where astrophage breathes.
如果我们靠近到五公里内， 我们会被撕成碎片，然后
Ted.
燃烧起来。游戏结束。
Oh. The problem is this ship wasn't built to go into the atmosphere.
游戏没结束。我制造锁链。 我制造长锁链。我把采集装置放在
If we get within five kilometers, we'll be ripped into a million pieces and then
上面。哦，是是是。五公里的锁链， 当然可以。废话！
we'll burn up. Game over.
像这条链子一样。看。
Game not over. I make chains. I make long chains. I put collection device on
你能做到这个？
hand. Oh, yeah, yeah. Five kilometers of chain, sure. Garbage!
能。效率真高。
Like this chain. Look.
那是什么？
You can do that?
哦！哦！
Yes. How efficient.
我看到了！
What's that?
什么？
Oh! Oh!
嗯，也许……在地球下面， 陆地就像钓鱼一样。
I see it!
我们非常靠近阿德里安大气层， 用锁链把采集器放入云层。
What?
然后格雷斯返回飞船把它收起来。 如果飞船角度和速度不精确， 我们就会死。举例！
Um, uh, maybe... Below Earth, land is like fishing.
我们必须反向飞行以保持适当的速度， 尽管格雷斯仍然有
We get very close to Adrian Atmosphere and lower Collector into clouds with
飞行员经验。
change. Then grapes go on haul to reel it in. If ship not at precise angle and
我一直在练习，不是吗？
speed, we die. Example!
再多点。不不不。 左边。向左。更左。更左。
We must fly backwards to keep proper velocities, even though Grace still has
完美了。不。
pilot experience.
错了。不。错方向。错方向。 错角度。不好，不好，不好。 好，好，好。
I've been practicing, haven't I?
好。不好。不够。不够。太多了。 太多了。太多了。我几乎要拉不动了。 不，不好。格雷斯罗基做了。全是罗基的。 所有的。
More. No, no, no. Left. Be left. More left. More left.
第一。死了。我们死了。我们死了。
It's perfect. No.
罗基已经建好了。
Wrong. No. Wrong way. Wrong way. Wrong angle. Bad, bad, bad. Good, good, good.
罗基的链子已经卷好待命。 格雷斯飞行员训练中。
Good. Bad. Not enough. Not enough. Too much. Too much. Too much. I'm barely
不够好。
pulling it. No, it's bad. Grace Rocky did. All Rocky. Plural. All.
什么东西，地球？
First. Die. We die. We die.
你好？他们听不到你，伙计。什么？ 我们实际上没有和地球通话。
Rocky has built.
地球太远了。你知道， 我们只是录下这些消息，告诉他们
Rocky chain spooled and ready. Grace pilot training.
我们学到了什么，然后 当我们完成后，我们会把它们全部发送回去
Not as good.
获得认可。为什么不 等你回家后自己告诉他们？有个问题。
What thing, Earth?
是的。
Hello? They can't hear you, pal. What? We're not actually talking to Earth.
对我来说，这是一张单程票，伙计。
Earth's too far away. You know, we just record these messages and we tell them
什么？我们有足够的燃料到达这里， 但没有足够的回去。
what we've learned and then when we're done, we'll send them all back and
那格雷斯会怎样？
approve. Why not you tell them yourself when you return home? Question.
有个问题。哦，我有足够的食物 至少支撑几年。也许如果我省着点用
Yeah.
还能多撑几年。
This is a one -way ticket for me, pal.
那格雷斯会死吗？
What? We had enough athletes to get here, but not enough to get back.
有个问题。是的，任务完成后， 我就会死。
So what happens, Grace?
你为什么没告诉我？
Question. Oh, I got enough food to last me at least a couple years. Maybe a
一时忘了。
couple more if I stretch it out.
不。格雷斯吃了格雷斯的「黄金」。
So Grace died?
我得以认识了你。
Question. Yeah, once we're done, I'm gonna die.
我做了所有这些了不起的事情。
Why didn't you tell me?
我挺好的。
It slipped my mind.
我已经接受了这件事。
No. Grace ate Grace's gold.
「接受」是什么意思？
I got to meet you.
意思是……我知道我不会变错。
I got to do all this amazing stuff.
我知道为什么。
I'm good.
而且没关系。
I've made peace with it.
大拇指朝上？不。小大拇指朝上？
What mean? What mean make peace?
不。
It means... I know I'm not going wrong.
我们还有星星要歌唱。
I know why.
好吗？
And it's okay.
帮助彼此。
Thumbs up? No. Tiny thumbs up?
嗯，蠢。
No.
太好了。
We got stars to sing.
在任何体育赛事上下注。 在扑克或赌场赢钱。
Okay?
攻克电竞赛事的赌注。 玩老虎机。你将能够
to help another.
买到你一直渴望的东西。 你还在等什么？
Uh, dumb.
去Annexbet网站，首次存款即可
Great.
获得100%奖金。
Pariez sur n 'importe quel événement sportif. Gagnez au poker ou au casino.
怎么了？
Attaquez les paris sur les cybersports. Jouez aux machines à sous. Et vous allez
这是一件人独自完成的事， 哦等等，我也是这样， 你就进来这里
pouvoir acheter ce que vous avez tellement voulu. Qu 'est -ce que vous
好吧
? Allez maintenant sur le site de Annexbet et obtenez un bonus de 100 %
你怎么知道拥抱结束了？ 你能感觉到。哦，
votre premier dépôt.
你现在感觉到了吗？没有。 哦，哦，好吧。是的。
What's happening?
今天早上我们再次进行了 防篡改模拟。 夏皮罗和杜波依斯又完美完成了。 好的。其他人怎么样？
something one does by themselves oh wait i do the same would you just get in
他们会准备好的。
here
我预计会的。
how
我有美好的未来。
do you know when the hug is done you just feel it oh
请接受这个称赞，好吗？
are you feeling it now no oh oh okay yeah
不。
We ran the tamper simulation again this morning. Shapiro and Dubois nailed it
这是命令。
again. Okay. What about the others?
好的。好的。
They'll be ready.
你觉得怎么样？
I expect so.
三天，相当令人印象深刻，
I have a great future.
是吧，是啊， 所以你接下来20年打算做什么， 有计划吗？
Can you take the compliment, please?
都很好。
No.
有什么问题吗？
It's an order.
没有，什么都没有。
Okay. Okay.
30000米外。探测器信号。好。
What do you think?
现在到了有趣的部分了。
pretty impressive three
这是个玩笑。
days
鼓励
huh yeah so
的
what are you gonna do for the next 20 years you got a plan
话语。
It's all good.
谢谢。
Any questions?
采集器应该很快就到了。
No, nothing.
是的。对。
30 ,000 meters out. Probe signal. Good.
太神奇了，太神奇了，太神奇了。
Now comes the fun part.
好，好，好。
It's a joke.
现在进入压力采集器。
Words
为什么不动了？
of
不，
encouragement.
格雷斯。
Thanks.
坏主意。进来。
Collector should be here soon.
我们一分钟后到。
Yeah. Yes.
不不不不不。格雷斯会死的。
Amaze, amaze, amaze.
你可以重新执行任务。你可以之后再试。 我不认为会有
Good, good, good.
激光。
Come inside the pressure collector now.
当然，当然，当然。 格雷斯会死。不不不。
Why not moving?
好好好好好。
No,
我有个主意。首先，不要撞。
Grace.
死了，没暴露。
Bad idea. Come inside.
痊愈了？痊愈了。
We'll be there in a minute.
谢谢你。
You can repeat missions. You can try again later. I don't think there is
一纳克的星噬体 不足以炸毁一栋楼。
to be a laser.
军需官错误地给了他们一毫克。 那是一亿倍
Of course, of course, of course. Grace will die. No, no, no.
他们准备承受的热能。 一个测量失误。
Good, good, good, good, good.
治好了我整个沉默。 不管怎样，我们必须发射。
I have an idea. First, no crash.
我们错过了轨道
Dead, not exposed.
窗口，让我们推迟了几个月。 是的，但如果没有人被训练来执行任务，
Heal? Heal.
这就无所谓了。 如果我们延迟，伤亡预测会呈指数级增长。 我们没有备选科学医生时间表。
Thank you.
好，但是……
One nanogram of astrophage isn't enough to blow up a building.
我需要一个熟悉星噬体的专家， 并且任务准备就绪。我还没准备好。
The quartermaster gave them one milligram by mistake. That's a billion
我没有接受任何训练。
heat energy that they're prepared for. A measuring mistake.
把它捡起来。
Healed my entire silency. It doesn't matter if we have to launch.
我不是宇航员。
We missed the orbital.
我是那种把「不」放进「宇航员」里的人。
window and set us back months. Yeah, but if no one's trained to do the mission,
我从来没做过任何事。 我从没太空行走过。我甚至不会月球漫步。
it won't matter. Casualty projections go up exponentially if we delay. We don't
我还没做过那个水池的事情。
have a schedule with a replacement science doctor.
不不不。这只是我们为了照片， 为了社交媒体做的事。
Okay, but...
我在任何方面都不英勇。 我坐电梯都会晕。
I don't need an astronaut.
完美。飞船上没有电梯。 我做不到这个。
I need an expert in astrophage who's mission ready. I'm not ready.
你很聪明。
I don't have any training.
你会想出来的。
Pick it up.
这对你来说可能很难理解， 但有些人是
I'm not an astronaut.
有些人不会在挑战中崛起。 你出席了我们关于任务的
I put the not in astronaut.
每一次重要的科学或战略会议。
I've never done anything. I've never done a spacewalk. I can't even moonwalk.
你遗漏了任务中一个重要的部分， 那就是自杀的部分。
I haven't done the whole pool thing.
格雷斯，你不去的话， 会有非常厉害的人陪伴你。
No, no, no. This is just we do for the picture, for social media.
你反正也会死的。
I'm not heroic in any way. I get sick on the elevator.
是的，但我死在30年后…… 和我们其他人一起。
Perfect. There's no elevator on the ship. I cannot do this.
你没有直系亲属。你甚至没有一条狗。
You're smart.
所以，我只是想确认一下， 你现在是在要求我
You'll figure it out.
放弃我的生命。
This might be very hard for you to understand, but some people are
是的。我们都是。
Some people don't rise to the challenge. You've been present for every major
我可以考虑一下吗？
scientific or strategic meeting we've had on the mission.
可以，女士。
You're missing out an important part of the mission, which is the suicide part.
我希望你醒来。
Grace, you'd be in very cool company if you don't go.
但是……你必须醒来。
You die anyway.
我不知道该怎么做。
Yeah, but I die in 30 years with... With the rest of us.
我想不出任何办法。
You have no immediate family. You don't even have a dog.
也许它们会吃掉我的头。
So, just so I'm clear, you're asking me right now to
我现在称它为鲸鱼座τ变形虫。
give up my life.
我相信当你醒来时你会 有很多话要说， 说这是一个
I am. We all are.
糟糕的名字。它只是来自鲸鱼座τ的变形虫， 我们在前面加了「τ」，
Can I think about this?
放在变形虫前面。但我想说， 这有一种优雅，一种简洁。
Yes ma 'am.
我们现在先不争论这个。 我们就先放一放，然后…… 我做了
I want you to wake up.
不同大气变量的测试，有趣的是， 每次我引入
But... You gotta wake up.
氮气，它就死了。
I'm not sure what to do.
我知道你在想，那太糟糕了， 因为这是个问题，
There's not anything I can think of.
因为我们需要它在 金星的条件下存活。
Maybe they might eat my head.
显然，我必须想出如何 培育一种新的耐氮
Right now I'm calling it Tau Meba.
变形虫菌株。
And I'm sure that when you wake up you'll have a lot to say about why
猜猜我用了什么？
bad name. It's just an amoeba from Tau Ceti and we're putting Tau in front of
我们用你的氙石制造的培育箱。
amoeba. But I would argue there's an elegance to that, a simplicity.
你知道吗？
Let's not fight about it now. Let's just, we'll table it and we'll... I did
现在我们只是一对非常酷的家伙， 拥有自己培育的
test of different atmospheric variables and fun fact, every time I introduced
耐氮变形虫菌株。
nitrogen, it died.
现在我们真正需要做的 就是繁殖足够多的来撑过旅程， 而你必须
And I know you're thinking, well, that's terrible because that's a problem
醒来，因为我不知道如何 处理你那一半的肚子里的空气。
because we needed to survive in the conditions of Venus.
所以，没有压力。
Obviously, I had to figure out how to breed a new strain of nitrogen
但我们确实有个约定。
amoeba.
她没有，嗯，她不知道。
And guess what I used?
她没有看到。
The breeder tanks that we made with your xenonite.
不，还没有。
And you know what?
太神奇了，太神奇了，太神奇了。
Now we're just a couple of very cool dudes with their very own strain of
罗基的培育箱设计。
nitrogen -resistant amoeba.
干得好，罗基。我们可以回家了。
Really all we have to do now is read enough to survive the trip and you gotta
声明。
wake up because I don't know how to get your half of the tummy to air it.
我来做。好好好。
So, no pressure.
那我们现在做什么？
But we did make a deal.
放弃。
She didn't, uh, she didn't know.
派对。
She didn't see it.
哇。
No, if yet.
我有特别的庆祝服装。
Amaze, amaze, amaze.
你让我觉得我必须，呃……什么？
Rocky breeder tank design.
停止我的游戏。
Good job, Rocky. We can go home.
这是什么？你不介意吗？
Statement.
罗基，罗基得到……就是这样。
I'll do it. Good, good, good.
是的，很好。
So what we do now?
我猜。
Quit.
不多。一点点东西。
Party.
你自己的笔记本电脑。
Wow.
我的便携式地球制造机！ 有所有的人类知识。
I get special clothing for celebration.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢。 还有最后一件事。
You're making me think that I have to, uh... What?
是的？
Stop my game.
罗基不能忘记。
What is this? You don't mind?
谢谢你。
Rocky, Rocky gets... There you go.
最终，你无法抹去它， 也无法替代它。
Yeah, good.
我在这里，我的朋友。
I guess.
我的位置在教室里。
Not much. A little something.
别再假装这是关于你学生的事了。 这太侮辱人了。
Very own laptop.
格雷斯，在接下来的40年里， 我们将失去世界四分之一的人口。
My portable earth -making machine! With all human knowledge.
年。
Thank you, thank you, thank you. And just one more thing.
这还是假设世界各国 共同合作来配给食物。
Yes?
我理解这些事情。
Rocky can't forget.
我明白。
Thank you.
但我没有那个能力。
In the end, you can't erase it, and you can't replace it.
我的决定已经做出。
Here I am, my friend.
抱歉，但是，呃……你说服我了。
My place is in the classroom.
我没有试图说服你任何事情。
Stop pretending this is about your students. It's so insulting.
我……正在努力让你理解 我接下来要做的事。
Grace, we will lose a quarter of the world's population in the next 40
任务档案会说我们提前 给你诱导昏迷是为了最大化你的安全。
years.
你将被铭记为英雄。
And that assumes that the nations of the world work together to ration food.
来吧。
I understand these things.
我必须这样做。来吧。
I do.
你在做什么？
But I don't have it in me.
这可能看起来像我背叛你， 但实际上是我相信你。 你
My mind is made up.
感觉你在背叛我。
I'm sorry, but, uh... You talked me into it.
请不要让这变得更难。来吧。
I'm not trying to talk you into anything.
让我们继续尝试。
I am... trying to make you understand what I'm
请坐下安静。
about to do next.
嗯！
Mission Sand will say that we induced your coma early to maximize your safety.
哦，是的，是的，它们运作得很好。
You will be remembered as a hero.
哦，太好了。
Come on.
开心，开心，开心。
I have to do this. Come on.
嗯……我的朋友。
What are you doing?
是的，朋友。
This may seem like me betraying you, but it's actually me believing in you. You
没那么兴奋，所以……
feel like you're betraying me.
看着你睡觉？
Don't make this harder, please. Come on.
是的。
Let's keep trying.
你非常勇敢。
Sit down and be quiet, please.
哦，我不知道这一点。
Buh!
你是我见过的最勇敢的人类。
Oh, yeah, yeah, they're working great.
嘿。这是个玩笑。我知道。
Oh, good.
我只认识一个人类，就是你。
Happy, happy, happy.
我明白了。
Well... My friend.
这是个好笑话。
Not so excited, so...
好了。
to watch you sleep?
那么……再见。
Yeah.
不明白这个词。
You are very brave.
还有，呃……再见了。
Oh, I don't know about that.
但我不会再见到你了。
You are the bravest human I have ever met.
我知道。
Hey. It's a joke. I know.
在你们家乡，你们是怎么说再见的？
I only meet one human, and it's you.
我们不说。
I get it.
我们这样做。
It's a good joke.
他们告诉我，如果我能撑过去。
All right.
我在它吃完船上所有星噬体之前 阻止了它。
Well... Bye.
罗基的飞船是用氙石建造的。
No understand word.
他们告诉我，它可能已经 进入了燃料管道。
And, uh... See you later.
它找不到泄漏， 因为泄漏就是飞船本身。
But I won't see you later.
它将没有任何燃料。
I know.
它被困住了。
How do you say goodbye back home?
它的生命维持系统将会失效。
We don't.
如果这不能杀死它， 辐射病会的。
We do this.
它面临漫长、缓慢、痛苦的死亡。
They tell me if I can get through it.
我无法两件事都做。
Probably because we brought it in the Xenonite breeder tanks. It evolved to
我可以回家。
escape it.
或者我可以拯救罗基。
I was able to stop it before it ate all the astrophysia on the ship.
我已经向你们发送了我们 所有发现的详细日志，以及 足够的鲸鱼座τ变形虫让你们
Rocky's ship is built of Xenonite.
开始自己的鲸鱼座τ变形虫农场。
They tell me if it will already be in its fuel lines.
至少我再也不用听你说「我早就说过了」。
It won't be able to find the leak because the leak is the ship itself.
尽管你就在我的生命中。
It'll be without any fuel.
始终如一。
It's stranded.
你和我周日驾车日。 不是晴朗的日子。始终如一。
His life support systems will fail.
谢谢你。
And if that doesn't kill him, the radiation sickness will.
不是
He's looking at a long, slow, painful death.
来自巴黎的罗基。
I can't do both.
我不是电影里的罗基。 不不不不。 我很确定他们知道这一点。
I can go home.
我留给你们所有发现的详细日志。
Or I can save Rocky.
我还加入了一点额外的东西，就为了好玩。
I've sent you detailed logs of all of our findings and enough Tau Miba for you
希望这一切都说得通。
to start your very own Tau Miba farm.
如果不行，这是马克。
At least I never have to hear you say, I told you so.
你们会想出来的。
Even though you're on my life.
这是
On and day.
瑞兰·格雷斯船长从万福玛利亚报告。
You and me Sunday drive day. Not a bright day. On.
正如欧里利安人所说。
Thank you.
为什么我总是要来得那么早？
isn't
是啊，我知道。
Rocky from Paris.
我劝勉你。
I am not Rocky from movie. No, no, no, no. I'm pretty sure they know that.
哦，是的。
I left you detailed logs of all of our findings.
嘿。
And I threw in a little something else just for fun.
为什么？我以为这是个安全的游戏。
Hopefully it all makes sense.
好的。
And if not, here's Mark.
阿曼多喜欢新鲜空气。
You'll figure it out.
我们能讨论一下水温吗？
This is Dr.
你能做到这件事本身就已经令人惊叹了。
Captain Rylan Grace reporting from Hail Mary.
非常冷。
As the Orillians say.
而且之前，是沸腾的。
Why do I always have to be so early?
有没有中间地带？
Yeah, I know.
请告诉生物穹顶照明团队， 现在已经完美了。
And I exhort you.
哦不，这是……你知道我 是无法抗拒雾气的。
Oh, yeah.
我能考虑一下吗？
Hey.
所有人就座。
Why? I thought this was a safe game.
醒来。
Okay.
谁能告诉我看见光？
Armando likes the fresh air.
阿曼多喜欢新鲜空气。
Can we talk about the water temperature a little bit?
我们能讨论一下水温吗？
It's amazing, just that you've done it at all.
你能做到这件事本身就已经令人惊叹了。
Very cold.
非常冷。
And before, it was boiling.
而且之前，是沸腾的。
Is there an in -between?
有没有中间地带？
Please tell the biodome illumination team that it's perfect now.
请告诉生物穹顶照明团队， 现在已经完美了。
Oh no, this is... You know I'm a sucker for the fog.
哦不，这是……你知道我 是无法抗拒雾气的。
Can I think about it?
我能考虑一下吗？
Everyone take their seats.
所有人就座。
Wake up.
醒来。
Who can tell me to see the light?
谁能告诉我看见光？